Hi everyone. Thanks for joining this
afternoon.
Um, I think we did a lot of good work in
free agency. In fact, I know we did and
it was a collaborative effort amongst
our operations staff, analytics,
scouting, coaching, everyone. Everyone
played a played a big role in in getting
all the work done that that we did and
we're all very proud of it. Uh, want to
give a special quick shout out to Jack
Chapman and and his content crew for
putting together those videos, the the
blueprint videos that we did. Uh, I
thought those were very well done. Uh,
hopefully our fans are excited about
about Jaylen and Devon. And obviously
there there's more good work to come out
of that crew.
Dave, Canalis, and Dan for their vision
um for free agency. It was it was
incredible to be a part of and and all
very exciting. And then of course the
tappers Dave and Nicole for for their
support and just their their excitement
over over all that that we've done. So
with that um just take everyone's
questions.
>> Questions for Brandt.
>> Hey Brandt. I'll start off. Hey, Alex.
>> Hey, man. Hope you're doing well. Um, I
wanted to start off by uh address or
having you address the decision to trade
Andy Dalton. Can you explain why it was
advantageous to do it at this time? Um,
as well.
>> Sure. uh with Andy. Um we signed Kenny
Picket and we want Kenny to be our
backup and Andy wanted the opportunity
to be a two somewhere else and um we did
the best we could to to find a good
opportunity for him uh and one that
would work out for us.
>> And and can you um talk about the timing
of it specifically? I know there are
financial implications of trading him
now versus trading him at a certain
point in the summer.
>> Sure, we could have, I guess, waited
until after June 1. The cap hit this
year would have been different, but it
would have been the same whether it was
just the the the totality of the cap
hits between this year and next year
would have been the same. So, the timing
wasn't all that important to us. it was
more important to whatever team was
trading for him that they get him in
their building and and acclimated
quicker. So the our best time, our best
value was to trade him now.
>> Got it. Thanks, man.
>> You're welcome.
>> Mike K followed by Desan.
I
>> think you're muted, Mike.
We will go with Desan.
>> Hi Brent. Thanks for taking the time.
>> Yeah,
>> I um
>> I heard you mention um I'm sorry I kind
of lost my train of thought there, but
one of the things I've seen you mention
previously was the team building process
in stages. I'm curious what stage you
feel that this team is in now and how
that impacted your approach during free
agency.
It's a great question. Uh, and it's
something that we talk a lot about here.
I I I look at the team building process
in three stages. It's building,
contending, and sustaining. And I and I
think of it like climbing up a mountain.
And I I think right now we're somewhere
between building and contending. And we
can see where it all plays out. We're
still adding good players to our roster.
um we are we are more competitive than
we have been in the past and we can just
see how it plays out from from there.
>> Thank you. My second part of that was
what impact does that have on your
approach when you are in that uh sort of
in between building and contending.
Yeah, there's there's obviously a lot of
uncertainty uh between the two and so I
think for us we're just we're just
trying to get as many good players on
the roster as possible and then we can
just we can see where it goes from
there. So you might see uh a little more
risk-taking now. Um
maybe um maybe just doing some some
different things like I think you guys
saw that we we converted Derek Brown's
contract and added a couple avoidables.
Like that's something that you wouldn't
necessarily do when you're in a
full-blown build. Uh but something that
that you can do as you're as you're
continuing your ascent up the mountain.
>> Thank you.
>> You're welcome.
>> We're gonna go with Joe Pson followed by
Phil Orbin.
Hey Brent, how you doing?
>> Hey Joe, I'm good. How are you?
>> Thanks for doing this. Um wondered uh
when we talked to you, I guess it was in
August I think you mentioned viewing
Bryce as an ascending player, kind of
still evaluating in terms of long-term
extension. Has anything changed uh
between August and and now as we sit
here in end of March?
No, nothing nothing's changed. Um, I got
the eval right. He was ascending. Um, so
nailed that. I was happy about that. Um,
but no, we haven't we we haven't had any
discussions with his agent about about a
contract and and any that that we that
we would have, we would just keep in
internal anyways. So, it's still the
same. Uh, still still evaluating and
just curious to see where where it all
goes and very excited about about Bryce
and all that he brings to us.
>> Would you think you might start those
before the the season, those
conversations with with his folks?
>> I'd never rule anything out, but I I
can't tell you affirmatively yes or no.
And then I want to ask you real quick
just where you guys had been in contract
negotiations with with Icky prior to his
injury. Are those on on hold now? Uh
with you know the timing of of his deal,
his injury.
>> Yeah, I'll I think just all all these
contract negotiations potential or
ongoing I'll just I'll just keep here
internally.
>> Thanks.
>> You're welcome.
>> Hey Brent. Um um Dan and Dave have both
spoken highly about the alignment
between the three of you and you
mentioned more risk takingaking as you
move from building to contending. How
how a as you begin to take more of those
risks?
How much do you rely on that trust and
that alignment among the three of you
even more? And how does it continue to
build as you continue to work together
uh for for more and more off seasons?
>> Yeah. Hey, Phil. Um
the trust that we have is is critical
and and
you know when we get into those
conversations Dave Dave Dan and I we
don't always agree but the trust is is
critical so that when we come out when
we come out of the discussion we're all
aligned we're all on the same page and
we fully support each other in the
decision that we're making and and we do
believe that whatever we do is in the
best interest of the organization even
if it's something that one of us wasn't
necessarily in favor of walking into the
room. So, yeah, having that trust to and
support from each other is is everything
with our with our decision-m process and
and it extends also to ownership. Like
they they have the the trust in us and
and they support us and um they've just
been great throughout throughout this
process, this free agency process, as
well as the last couple of years here.
Thanks, Brandon. You're welcome.
>> We'll go with Darren Gant, followed by
David Newton.
>> Brent, going back to your three stages,
I mean, you lived going from contend to
sustain in Kansas City. What are kind of
the critical steps in there and what's
that adjustment like when you do get to
that point?
Yeah, the contending to s sustaining
probably means dipping your toe uh less
in free agency and it's more about
retaining your own players who you've
drafted and relying on the draft to
bring in your your talented players.
It's it's a hard stage to get to and and
not many teams do and and I hope we get
there.
>> Grant David here. Uh kind of follow up
on that. Mark Dan said that uh he could
tell the difference in players wanting
to come to Carolina from when y'all
first got there to now. Um, how from
your viewpoint in negotiations did did
that stand out?
>> Um,
from from a negotiation standpoint, it
really just got us, I'll call it, a seat
at the table with with these players.
Um, you know, before like my my first
year here, our first year here, it w we
we had to to really sell the build in
Carolina and the vision. And now players
players see it. So there there was less
uh recruiting, but at the same time,
like it was still a contract
negotiation. We weren't cut any breaks.
Nobody cut us a deal, a break or
anything like that. we we just were able
to get to the answers quicker.
>> Well, did you see incidents where I mean
there were some instance where maybe a
player got offered more somewhere else
but he wanted to play at Carolina
because of what you're building that you
got maybe a a little bit of a break
there?
>> No. And No, and that's that's very
unusual for that to happen anywhere.
That that didn't even happen to us in
Kansas City when when we were really
humming there. So, typically if a player
wants to be here,
uh, the agent will will just do his best
to to get the best possible deal with us
and then compare that to the other deals
and and see see where that goes. But
even if there was a discount given, I
would never even know about it and and I
I just don't I don't suspect that it's
that it's happening.
>> Okay. Right. I appreciate it. Thanks a
lot.
>> You're welcome. Um, Brandt, I'll just go
ahead with uh my question here. Um, so I
understand that you're keeping all
contract negotiations in in-house. I
understand that. Uh, but just speaking
generally about a guy like Jaylen Coker,
someone who has um proven that he wants
to be in Carolina, proven that he can be
really a really productive receiver. How
do you balance wanting to keep him for
the long term, but also, you know, uh,
facing the realities of, okay, he's an
exclusive rights free agent. This means
he is, um, there are certain ways to
negotiating to to negotiate with him in
these sorts of ways. How do you balance
those things, particularly with a guy
like Jaylen?
I I'll just speak generally just about
all player contracts here and any any
that that we do so that we kind of avoid
Jaylen in particular. But with any deal,
we're looking at what's it going to take
to secure this player services over
whatever number of years
and
how does that affect our ability to keep
to keep this team together and add to it
if necessary. and and we're also looking
at at alternatives, you know, is there
an alternative to this player who we
could find in the draft or in free
agency. So,
we're kind of balancing all of that and
and figuring out all right, what's like
what's what's the right value there and
what's our what's our best course of
action here moving forward.
>> Um, got it. And then I also wanted to
ask about um Jaylen Phillips, another
Jaylen. Um he so I'm looking at his over
the cap right now. His base salary is
1.2 million in 2026 and then that
gradually increases over the time and it
ultimately comes out to the um to the
120 million number over four years that
has that was reported.
What can you and perhaps forgive me for
shedding my ignorance here, but can you
explain to me the advantages of having
of having the contract kind of set up
like that?
>> The the advantage is that's something
that we've done since I got here. So,
what what you what you really want when
you're structuring contracts and and cap
numbers and things like that is you just
want consistency with all your deals.
And that's what we've done with with
Jayen's deal. It's what we've done with
all of our deals. You'll see we we do
minimum P5s and then and then a pretty
large signing bonus. And uh I've just
found that that's that's the best way to
uh to balance your your cap and your
cash and um and that's just how we've
done it and how we're going to continue
to be doing it going forward.
>> Got it. Thanks, man.
>> We have time for a couple more. We'll go
with Nicholas Carboni followed by Phil
Orbin.
Hey Brent, good afternoon. Wondering why
at this point in the build of the team
was the right time for you guys to go
after a premium position like pass
rusher with Jaylen Phillips and um you
know maybe he doesn't come in with the
double digit sack numbers yet, but what
kind of parameters and um things did you
see from him that made it worthy of the
contract that you guys gave?
For the last three years, we've we've
been going after what we believe are the
best players in free agency. So, it just
so happened that Jaylen Phillips played
a premium position. That's what made him
so enticing was that he was an impact
player who played a premium position
and and so whoever the impact players
were in free agency the last three years
were the ones who who we were we were
going after. Um, so I I think it was
more about his talent and less about the
position he played. I think if he if if
there was an impact player at really at
any position, we were we were going to
be interested in that in that player.
>> Thank you.
>> Welcome.
>> Hey Brent, um, back to the back to the
three steps, if you'll indulge me. Okay.
To get to the sustain process, do you
have to begin that sort of build for
that while you're in the contending
phase? Like is that something that you
have to begin to start the process of
and then hope that that contending stage
gets there?
>> Um, it's a another good question.
Um,
I don't really want to box myself in to
say that it has to be one one way or the
other, but it it is a reason why
one-year deals uh are re it's really
hard to
um to sustain anything when you're when
you're signing a bunch of big money long
ter one-year deals. Uh you really want
long-term deals to to sustain and you
also need to be able to continue to to
draft well. So, so I'm just kind of
talking through this now stream of
conscious with you here and I it's
really it really comes down to drafting
well and having a really good process
and you know if if we have that then
yeah I think we can we can get pretty
pretty close to that sustaining level.
>> Appreciate it.
>> We will end with Joe Pson followed by
Mike K.
Brandt, you guys are pretty tight
against the cap, at least according to
these these industry databases. Um, will
you have to look at someone like JC for
a restructure or do you have some other
things in mind in terms of getting
enough to to sign your draft picks?
>> Yeah, we are going to have to make room.
Um, we we we could convert JC. We could
convert a few other players if we chose.
We have a few different avenues and
we're just weighing them all. But but
like the overarching thing with us is we
would rather not do those things until
we have to. So it may just be some time
before you see what that looks like.
>> Hey Brent, hopefully you can hear me
now.
>> I can hear you.
>> I'm not frozen.
>> Um so you brought up P5s, you brought up
one-year deals. How much did the veteran
minimum benefit help you guys in in kind
of collecting this roster of retaines?
And how in general did Jaylen Phillips
being kind of a force multiplier, a guy
who could affect other people play into
your decision in evaluating his talent?
>> All right. All right. So, with the with
the VSB guys, um those are players that
we get a cap credit for uh if we sign
them to deals that follow certain
parameters. And it's it's a tool that's
very useful for uh for us. Um we've used
we've been using it since I've been
here. We used it a lot in Kansas City as
well. So, it's it is it is helpful. Uh
it's a great way to to keep your depth.
uh consistent.
So that was that was helpful. Um and
then your other question was about
Jaylen. Can you remind me what that was?
I'm sorry.
>> Yeah, just him being kind of a force
multiplier, a guy that can can impact
other people, make other people better
around him because of what he does well.
Yeah, that's that's what Dan and and
Dave saw out of him was the the ability
to to get after the passer and and apply
pressure so that you know the ball's
coming out quicker. We're able to make
more plays on the ball. Uh we're able to
to ideally get off the field sooner.
like all of those things come into play
and and we just felt like with Jaylen it
was it was a unique opportunity to get a
player of that level at that position.
So we we
were just very fortunate that that he
agreed to come here.
>> And then uh one last one. Yeah,
>> there's I don't know if it's
unprecedented, but there are a lot of
teams that have multiple first round
picks
>> and a lot of teams that have like kind
of geared up on second and third round
picks.
>> Does that make trading back and trading
up easier for a team analytically or is
that just kind of where this this year
is going with the weight of this draft?
>> I haven't really thought about it like
that. Um,
I don't even know. I couldn't even tell
you at the top of my head how many teams
behind us have multiple ones. Um,
but yeah, you usually
usually teams that have multiple picks
in a round are more are more likely to
trade. So, I I could certainly see there
being more first round trades this year.
That's possible. Uh, it's not anything
that we've really thought about as far
as like targeting trades. Usually with
trades on draft day, it's it usually
just comes down to calling your friends
and seeing if they're willing to do a
deal or not. Uh, those are the ones that
that tend to work the the best for uh
for both sides, but um yeah, I haven't
really thought about how that how the
multiple ones would affect us.
All right, Brandt, that's all the
questions that we have for you today.
Cool. Thanks for taking
>> Thanks, everyone.